

☑ jeromewus@gmail.com | 🄏 jeromewu.github.io | ☑ jeromewu | 🛅 wenchiehwu | 🐚 jeromewus

Summary .

Passionate problem solver, technology enthusiast, compassionate leader with 5+ years as software engineer and architect and 3+ years as technical lead in multidisciplinary environments.

Excel in leadership, critical thinking, communication and software engineering & architecture. Strong skills in JavaScript (incl. React, Express), Golang, Docker and CI/CD pipelines. Major contributor of tesseract.js (21k+ stars on Github) and ffmpeg.wasm. Certified architecting, data engineering, big data and machine learning specializations in Google Cloud Platform.

Work Experience

INTELLLEX Singapore

TECHNICAL LEAD Apr. 2019 - PRESENT

Led a technical team to develop knowledge systems

Delta Electronics Taipei City, Taiwan

SOFTWARE ARCHITECT & PRODUCT MANAGER

May 2019 - PRESENT

- · Established a cross-region project team with 10+ members to research and develop an edge computing solution in manufacturing industry.
- · Designed a microservice software architecture for edge computing solution to enable flexiblity and scalibility.
- · Adopted gitlab-CI and Ansible to deploy microservices in Kubernetes cluster to minize deployment efforts.
- Developed a tensorflow serving like interface library in Golang.

SENIOR TECHNICAL LEAD Feb. 2018 - May 2019 (1 year 4 months)

- Established a corss-region team of engineers, designers and QA with 20+ members in charge of front-end development.
- Implemented working model for cross team collaboration and guidelines for engineers and designers.
- · Led team to develop over 10 applications at the same time, 2 of them attract hundreds of users internally and improve work performance.
- Implemeted API microservices with ExpressJS and deployed as AWS Lambda functions.
- Incubated 3 senior developers to become team leaders leading regional team members.

Technical Lead Apr. 2016 - Feb. 2018 (1 year 11 months)

- Established a team of engineers with 9+ members in charge of innovative software research and development.
- Defined and promoted in-house UI framework to all front-end developers.
- Designed and built up CI/CD pipelines with gitlab, gitlab-CI, docker, ansible and more.
- Designed and deployed applications to AWS cloud environment
- Implemented RESTful API guideline to enable consistent API design across applications.
- · Led and implemented 3 projects with React and promoted to organization to boost work performance

Senior Project Engineer Sep. 2014 - Apr. 2016 (1 year 8 months)

- Member of Strategy and Innovation Research team which was under CTO to research for enterprise transformation.
- Developed application prototypes with React to demonstrate concepts to Delta senior managers (incl. CEO, CTO and COO) and got positive feedback in both 2015 and 2016.
- Operated 2 internal projects which transfers to BU/BG after incubation stage.

IKV Technology Taipei City, Taiwan

SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERNSHIP

Sep. 2013 - Aug. 2014 (1 year)

• Implemented Bitcoin wallet related features.

ETS-Lindgren Taipei City, Taiwan

SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERNSHIP

Mar. 2011 - May 2012

• Rewrote and enhanced signal processing algorithm and implement GUI in C#.

Education

National Taiwan University

Taipei City, Taiwan

MASTER'S DEGREE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND INFORMATION ENGINEERING

Sep. 2013 - Sep. 2014

Got ACM 2014 Research in Adaptive and Convergent Systems (RACS '14) Best Paper Award (paper acceptance rate 23.5%.)

WEN-CHIEH WU · RÉSUMÉ

Honors & Awards

2020	Best PM Award, Delta Research Center	Taipei City, Taiwan	
2016	Judge, The InnoServe Awards 2016	Taipei City, Taiwan	
2015	Delta Electronics Representative, W3C Web of Things F2F Meeting	San Francisco, U.S.A	
2014	Best Paper Award, 2014 Research in Adaptive and Convergent Systems (RACS '14). ACM	Towson, U.S.A	
2014	Speaker, Hack in Taiwan Conference (HITCON) 2014	Taipei City, Taiwan	
2011	Outstanding College Youth, Outstanding College Youth of National Taiwan University	Taipei City, Taiwan	

Certifications __

2020	We recommend AWS Fundamentals by Amazon Web Services on Coursera. Certificate earned at	AWS	
	06/28/2020, AWS	ANS	
2020	Deep Learning by deeplearning.ai on Coursera. Certificate earned at March 2, 2020, deeplearning.ai	Andrew Ng	
2020	Programming with Google Go by University of California, Irvine on Coursera. Certificate earned at		
	January 12, 2020, University of California, Irvine	lan Harris	
2019	Data Engineering, Big Data, and Machine Learning on GCP, a 5-course specialization by Google Cloud		
	on Coursera. Specialization Certificate earned on August 11, 2019, Google Cloud Training	Google Cloud	
2019	Architecting with Google Cloud Platform, a 6-course specialization by Google Cloud on Coursera.	Google Cloud	
	Specialization Certificate earned on August 6, 2019, Google Cloud Training		
2019	Digital Business Strategy: Harnessing Our Digital Future, MIT Sloan School of Management	MIT	
2012	Leadership Development Program, National Taiwan University	National Taiwan	
	Leadership Development Program, National Talwan Oniversity	University	
2012	Cloud Computing Program, National Taiwan University	National Taiwan	
	Cloud Computing Program, inational failwan onliversity	University	

Side Projects _____

ffmpeg.wasm

https://github.com/ffmpegwasm/ffmpeg.wasm

Owner

Oct. 2019 - PRESENT

Feb. 2018 - PRESENT

• ffmpeg.wasm is a pure Webassembly / Javascript port of FFmpeg. It enables video & audio record, convert and stream right inside browsers.

Tesseract.js

https://github.com/naptha/tesseract.js

CONTRIBUTOR

• Tesseract.js is a pure Javascript port of the popular Tesseract OCR engine. It supports over 100 languages, automatic text orientation and script detection, a simple interface for reading paragraph, word, and character bounding boxes. Tesseract.js can run either in a browser and on a server with NodeJS.

• 21k+ stars in Github.

VCLink Web Development

https://vclink.com/

DEVELOPER

Sep 2018 - Feb 2019

• VCLink is a co-investment platform built by VSC Ecosystem (VSC) where qualified investors can co-invest alongside VSC and trusted anchor VCs in carefully selected early-stage deals.

FGO Calculator

https://github.com/jeromewu/fgo-

calc

 Owner
 Feb 2018 – May 2018

• A calculator helps you to calculate the overall resource left in events.

Skills

Strong React, Emscripten, HTML5, CSS3, Docker, Gitlab CI, Golang, Kubernetes, AWS, Terraform

Knowledgeable Vue, Java, Python, Ansible, Latex, Bitcoin, Software Architecture Design, GCP

Languages Chinese, English